Now we've gone over some techniques for getting to a high level concept for
现在 我们仔细学习了获得指标高级概念的一些技巧
a metric, and then translating that into a specific data measurement, and
然后将其转化为具体的数据测量指标
also evaluating possible filters.
并评估可用的筛选器
And a while ago you also mentioned summary metrics.
刚才你提到了总指标
What are those?
什么是总指标？
>> Well so what we have so far are direct data measurements.
我们目前所拥有的是直接的数据测量指标
This can be a page view, a click measure of latency for a particular event.
可能是网页浏览量 也可能是某个事件的延迟的点击测量
And what we want to do, at this point is,
我们此刻想要做的是
to summarize all of these individual events into a single summary metric.
将所有这些独立的事件汇总为一个总指标
Now in some cases, the summary metric is really obvious.
在这些情况下 总指标很明显
For example, if you're counting how many cookies are visiting the homepage,
例如 如果你计算有多少 cookies 访问了主页
it's a count, or a sum of just the total count, right?
这是一个总量计数或总数 对吧？
You can also summarize that further into something like, you know,
你还可以进一步总结为 例如
the average number of visitors per week.
每周平均访客数量
Now for a rate or a probability,
现在对于一个点击率或点击概率
if you actually look at the specific computation, it's actually computing
如果你看具体的计算 实际上计算的是
an average over the clicks per page view for every single individual effect.
每个单独的个体效应对每个网页浏览的平均点击量
Now in all of those cases,
现在 在所有情况下
the summarization is actually part of the metric definition.
总结实际上是指标定义的一部分
But there's a whole bunch of other cases where you actually have a choice
但还有很多其他情况 你可以选择
of summary metric.
总指标
>> Okay. What are some examples of that?
好的 能列举一些示例吗？
>> Well the primary situation that that occurs,
好的 主要情况是
is when your per event measurement is itself a number.
当你的每个事件测量指标是一个数字时
And this is something like the load time of a video, or how many terms are in
就像一个视频的加载时间 或一个查询中有多少术语
a query, or what the position of the first click on the page is.
或网页上第一次点击在哪里
Now when you have a number like that,
现在 当你拥有那样一个数字时
you have a whole set of metrics to choose from.
你就拥有一整套可以选择的指标
For example, the mean, the median, the 25th percentile, the 70th percentile,
例如 平均值、中位数、25%、70%
the 90th percentile.
90%
You can choose any of those types of metrics to actually summarize
你可以选择任何一类指标 来总结
your individual events.
独立的事件
>> So how would you choose between these different options?
那么 你如何在不同的方案间选择呢？
>> Well so what you're going to do is,
你要做的是
you're going to establish a few characteristics for your metric.
为你的指标确定一些特征
The first one is going to be the sensitivity and robustness.
第一个是敏感性和稳健性
You want your metric to be sensitive enough, in order to actually detect
你想使你的指标足够敏感
a change when you, when you're testing your possible future options, right?
从而在你测试你未来可能的方案时 能够发现变更 对吗？
The second that you're going to want to characterize is what the distribution
第二个是要描述
of your metric looks like, and that's going to help you choose.
你指标的分布是什么样子 这有助于你选择
>> Okay. Can you elaborate on that?
好的 你能够详细说明吗？
What kind of things do I need to do to characterize the distribution?
我需要做什么来描述指标分布？
>> The most ideal way of doing this is to do a retrospective analysis, and
描述它的最理想的方式是进行回顾性分析
to compute a histogram.
并计算直方图
Now what a histogram is,
现在直方图是
is that on the x axis you have all of the different values for your metric.
在 x 轴上 你拥有指标的所有值
So for example, you're going to have all the different values for
例如 你在 x 轴上的加载时间
load time on the x axis.
有不同的值
The y axis is going to be the frequency,
y 轴代表频率
so how often individual events have that particular load time.
独立事件出现那个特定加载时间的频率如何
When you actually plot that histogram,
当你绘制直方图时
you get a shape, that's going to be your distribution.
你会得到一个形状 这就是你的指标分布
And what you're looking at is what that shape is.
你需要看看是什么形状
If it's a very normal shape, then a mean or
如果是一个非常正常的形状 那平均值或
median's going to make a lot of sense.
中位数会非常有用
As it becomes more one sided, or lopsided, you might want to go more for
随着它比较片面 或变得不平衡 你可能要使用
a 25th, or a 75th, or a 90th percentile.
25%、75% 或 90%
That's going to also depend a lot
这在很大程度上取决于
on what change it is that you actually want to test.
你想要测试的更改是什么
Now I think you're going to be going over these, some of the simple ones,
现在 我想你需要重温这些内容 有些简单的内容
in much more detail, in the next video.
在下一个视频中有更详细地讲解
And in the Instructor's Note we have a lot more details about
在讲师注释中 我们有关于其他分布
some of the other distributions that can occur.
的更详细的讲解
>> Okay.
好的
And do you have any general categories of metrics that you
你在脑海中会有对这些指标的
like to keep in mind?
大概分类吗？
>> There's four categories that I like to keep in mind.
这里有四类我想记住的指标
The first one are the sums and counts.
第一类是合计和计数
This is, like, how many cookies visit the homepage.
就像有多少 cookies 访问了主页
The second one is going to be all of the distributional metrics: the means,
第二类是所有分布指标
the medians, the 25th, the 75th and 90th percentiles.
平均值、中位数、25%、75% 和 90%
The third category is going to be probabilities and rates.
第三类是点击概率和点击率
We've talked about those a lot in these past couple of lessons.
我们在前两节中讲了很多
And the fourth one is ratios.
第四类是比例
Ratios are very, very useful, because they can compute a whole range of
比例十分有用 因为它们能够计算各种不同的业务模式
different business models, and various different things that you may care
和你可能关心的各种不同的事情
about, but they can be very difficult to characterize.
但很难描述其特征
>> Okay.
好的
Let's go over an example before we move on to sensitivity and robustness.
在讲敏感性和稳健性之前 我们先来看一个示例